<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ESP32 on xyzroe's blog</title><link>/tags/esp32/</link><description>Recent content in ESP32 on xyzroe's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/esp32/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ESP32 C6 D1</title><link>/posts/esp32_c6_d1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/esp32_c6_d1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Unleash the future of wireless connectivity with &lt;strong&gt;ESP32 C6 D1&lt;/strong&gt; — a compact, feature-packed dev board crafted in the iconic Wemos D1 form factor, designed for developers craving speed, efficiency, and versatility.&lt;br&gt;
Built on Espressif’s cutting-edge ESP32-C6, this board supercharges your IoT projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✅ Wemos D1 Form Factor – Seamless compatibility with existing shields, sensors, and accessories.&lt;br&gt;
✅ RISC-V Core – High performance (160 MHz) meets energy efficiency for battery-powered brilliance.&lt;br&gt;
✅ 10 GPIOs – SPI, I2C, UART, PWM, and ADC pins for endless hardware hacks. + UART pins&lt;br&gt;
✅ USB-C (PROG + JTAG) + Onboard WS2812 LED – Plug, play, and debug with modern convenience.&lt;br&gt;
✅ Wi-Fi 6 + Bluetooth 5 LE + 802.15.4 Zigbee/Thread&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ZigUSB С6</title><link>/posts/zigusb_%D1%816/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/zigusb_%D1%816/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ZigUSB C6 project is an innovative solution designed to enhance the control and monitoring of USB-powered devices through Zigbee communication. This project aims to provide a seamless integration for smart home enthusiasts and professionals alike, enabling remote control, automation, and monitoring of USB devices in a Zigbee-enabled ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is based on the original ZigUSB but uses a modern chip and custom-developed firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this device, you can remotely control the power of the USB port to turn on or off the connected device. Additionally, you can monitor the current voltage and current. It also functions as a reliable Zigbee network router.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>XZG Firmware</title><link>/posts/xzg_fw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/xzg_fw/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Zigbee gateways for a while now, experimenting with different ESP32-based projects and CC2652 coordinators. Each one had its strengths — some excelled at MQTT integration, others at web interfaces or specific hardware support — but switching between them or trying to combine features was a hassle. Too many fragmented efforts meant slower progress for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I created XZG Firmware. It&amp;rsquo;s a unified solution that brings together the best innovations from various Zigbee gateway projects into one codebase. By consolidating efforts on a single, open-source firmware, we can focus on making it better: more features, better stability, easier setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>