<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>xyzroe's blog</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/</link><description>Recent content on xyzroe's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//xyzroe.cc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lumi Router JN5169</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/lumi-router-jn5169/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/lumi-router-jn5169/</guid><description>Lumi Router This is fork of Lumi Router JN5169 firmware for use with the LM15-SP-WM module used in the Xiaomi Smart Plug (ZNCZ02LM).
Also it can be used with any other JN5169 based module.
The only difference is the ability to reset the device using a button on DIO 0.
In the original firmware, all control takes place only through the serial port.
How to flash Download JN-SW-4107 and install Connect using JP1 to your USB-TTL according to table below: LM15-SP-WM (JP1) JN5169 Function USB-TTL 1 DIO 28 TXD0 RX 2 DIO 29 RXD0 TX 3 DIO 22 SPIMISO GND 4 DIO 9/39 VDD 3.</description></item><item><title>Doorphone opener Zintercom</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zintercom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zintercom/</guid><description>Board v2 available at GitHub Today I want to share with you the history of the development of a device for controlling a multi-apartment intercom using the Zigbee protocol.
Once upon a time I had an automatic doorphone opener based on: ESP8266, a module for two relays (16A) and a transistor with a strapping.
All this was collected on a bunch of wires and snot made of hot melt glue and looked something like the second photo.</description></item><item><title>oko2mqtt</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/oko2mqtt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/oko2mqtt/</guid><description>During the New Year holidays, we got around to finishing and posting on GitHub the code that allows you to raise your TCP server for OKO devices with state transfer and the ability to control via MQTT. 💡
The MQTT AutoDiscovery mechanism has been implemented, which allows you to automatically add all devices / inputs / outputs / sensors to HomeAssistant. Supports work simultaneously with multiple devices, multithreading.
Currently, support for expansion cards and radio sockets is limited.</description></item><item><title>AirPrint with Epson TM-T20II</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/cups-airprint-epson-tm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/cups-airprint-epson-tm/</guid><description>Ubuntu Xenial Docker image with CUPS and additional Epson TM-T20II drivers It is intended to be used as an AirPrint relay on the Synology NAS, and the local Avahi will be used to advertise printers on the network.
Changes in comparison with the original:
updated version of Ubuntu added prebuilt rastertozj from here added tm-t20-orig.ppd is tm-t20ii-rastertotmt.ppd provided on Epson site modifited to use rastertozj filter added tm-t20-NP.ppd to make possible print Nova Poshta Zebra Markings 100x100mm from iOS browser (with image scaling) added tm-t20-TG.</description></item><item><title>Using LED P-10 to display txt file</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/led_p10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/led_p10/</guid><description>I need to display actual number of tickets in our service support system using big LED display. 🚨
I found LED P10 modules, they are cheap and nice, different colors available. Modules can be connected one by one to make big screen.💡
Then I need some hardware to connect to P-10 and I found VBC-P10 module from great Ukrainian 🇺🇦 manufacture VK Module. But it has only RS485 and TTL ports, while I need Ethernet so I add Ethernet - RS485 converter.</description></item><item><title>Alco Post</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/alcopost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/alcopost/</guid><description>Hardware and software complex of the checkpoint 1 turnstile any 2 controllers ZK MA300 2 alcotesters Alcofor S40 1 speaker and LED unit with voice prompts and mode indication 1 orange pi with python utility for displaying photos and status of passing through the turnstile and writing to the database order of actions: authorization to ZK - alcohol test - in case of an error again - in case of an error, again record the violation and refusal to work (or notification of dismissal, but with permission to exit) - record a successful passage and farewell.</description></item><item><title>WP Matador recovery</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/matador/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/matador/</guid><description>Deck ovens for baking bread manufactured by WP Matador.
Year of release 1995.
A complete overhaul was carried out with the replacement of all executive units, including complete disassembly, replacement-welding of metal, cleaning, primer-painting, assembly, insulation with mineral wool, installation of cladding.
Burners - gas, new Giersch RG20.
The control panels are made from scratch according to our own design.
Light - 4 incandescent lamps 50W, soft start, timer shutdown.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/about/</guid><description>This is a personal blog.
I am going to share information about projects in which I happened to participate or implemented by myself.
Something will be just interesting, perhaps some information will be useful,
also there will be projects that, if you like, you can repeat it exactly as instructed.
If you liked the information posted here or found it helpful, you can say thanks using links below:</description></item></channel></rss>