<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>USB on xyzroe's blog</title><link>/tags/usb/</link><description>Recent content in USB on xyzroe's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/usb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ZigUSB ะก6</title><link>/posts/zigusb_%D1%816/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/zigusb_%D1%816/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ZigUSB C6 project is an innovative solution designed to enhance the control and monitoring of USB-powered devices through Zigbee communication. This project aims to provide a seamless integration for smart home enthusiasts and professionals alike, enabling remote control, automation, and monitoring of USB devices in a Zigbee-enabled ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is based on the original ZigUSB but uses a modern chip and custom-developed firmware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this device, you can remotely control the power of the USB port to turn on or off the connected device. Additionally, you can monitor the current voltage and current. It also functions as a reliable Zigbee network router.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ZigUSB</title><link>/posts/zigusb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/zigusb/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="new-version-of-this-device---zigusb-c6"&gt;New version of this device - &lt;a href="https://github.com/xyzroe/ZigUSB_C6"&gt;ZigUSB C6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZigUSB was developed as a device that allows you to control and monitor the power of a device connected via USB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this device, you can remotely control the power of the USB port to turn on or off the connected device. And also monitor the current voltage and current. And it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad Zigbee network router.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequent use cases: converting a &amp;ldquo;stupid&amp;rdquo; USB lamp into a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; one; connecting modems / sticks / adapters, which sometimes require a power reset; monitoring the current consumption of any connected device.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>