<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DIY on xyzroe's blog</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/tags/diy/</link><description>Recent content in DIY on xyzroe's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//xyzroe.cc/tags/diy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ZigUSB</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zigusb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zigusb/</guid><description>ZigUSB was developed as a device that allows you to control and monitor the power of a device connected via USB.
Using this device, you can remotely control the power of the USB port to turn on or off the connected device. And also monitor the current voltage and current. And it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad Zigbee network router.
Frequent use cases: converting a &amp;ldquo;stupid&amp;rdquo; USB lamp into a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; one; connecting modems / sticks / adapters, which sometimes require a power reset; monitoring the current consumption of any connected device.</description></item><item><title>ZigUNO</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/ziguno/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/ziguno/</guid><description>ZigUNO is a development board for creating DIY Zigbee devices based on Ebyte E18-MS1 module (CC2530)
Physically, the board is compatible with all shields of the Uno form factor. Finally you can use countless old Arduino shields 🤣
As a firmware, it is proposed to use:
Zigbee configurable firmware PTVO 🚀 Develop your own using ZigUP or one of the various DIYRuZ projects as examples Usefull links A beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to using PTVO is available on Habr (in russian) A beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide to developing your own Zigbee firmware is available on Habr (in russian) A complete guide showing how to install IAR to start developing your own firmware is available on ZigDevWiki ZigUNO is certified open source hardware project Overview v1.</description></item><item><title>Lumi Router JN5169</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/lumi_router/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/lumi_router/</guid><description>Lumi Router This is fork of Lumi Router JN5169 firmware for use with the LM15-SP-WM module used in the Xiaomi Smart Plug (ZNCZ02LM).
Also it can be used with any other JN5169 based module.
The only difference is the ability to reset the device using a button on DIO 0.
In the original firmware, all control takes place only through the serial port.
How to flash Download JN-SW-4107 and install Connect using JP1 to your USB-TTL according to table below: LM15-SP-WM (JP1) JN5169 Function USB-TTL 1 DIO 28 TXD0 RX 2 DIO 29 RXD0 TX 3 DIO 22 SPIMISO GND 4 DIO 9/39 VDD 3.</description></item><item><title>Doorphone opener Zintercom</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zintercom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/zintercom/</guid><description>Board v2 available at GitHub Today I want to share with you the history of the development of a device for controlling a multi-apartment intercom using the Zigbee protocol.
Once upon a time I had an automatic doorphone opener based on: ESP8266, a module for two relays (16A) and a transistor with a strapping.
All this was collected on a bunch of wires and snot made of hot melt glue and looked something like the second photo.</description></item><item><title>Using LED P-10 to display txt file</title><link>//xyzroe.cc/posts/led_p10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//xyzroe.cc/posts/led_p10/</guid><description>I need to display actual number of tickets in our service support system using big LED display. 🚨
I found LED P10 modules, they are cheap and nice, different colors available. Modules can be connected one by one to make big screen.💡
Then I need some hardware to connect to P-10 and I found VBC-P10 module from great Ukrainian 🇺🇦 manufacture VK Module. But it has only RS485 and TTL ports, while I need Ethernet so I add Ethernet - RS485 converter.</description></item></channel></rss>